A Finding Aid to the Anna Coleman Ladd Papers, 1881-1950, in the Archives of American Art AAA.laddanna
Archives of American Art
Anna Coleman Ladd papers
1881-1950
AAA.laddanna
Archives of American Art
4.2 Linear feet
The papers of sculptor Anna Coleman Ladd measure 4.2 linear feet, date from 1881-1950, and document the career of sculptor Anna Coleman Ladd. Found within the papers are biographical material, letters, diaries, financial material, notes and writings, art work, a file concerning the American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks, scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Ladd, Anna Coleman
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Anna Coleman Ladd papers were donated in 1991 by William Terry on behalf of Robert Edwards, a friend of Anna Coleman Ladd.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Biographical/Historical note
Born in 1878 in Philadelphia to John and Mary Watts, Anna Coleman Ladd (née Watts) was educated in private schools and Europe. She also studied in America under Charles Grafly.
She moved to Boston in 1905 and married Boston pediatrician Maynard Ladd with whom she had two daughters, Gabriella May Ladd and Vernon Abbott Ladd. Working in her studio on Clarendon Street, Ladd became one of the city's most prolific sculptors, creating fountain pieces, portrait busts, memorials, and reliefs in addition to authoring two novels, Hieronymus Rides in 1912, and The Candid Adventurer in 1913.
Between 1907 and 1915, Ladd had solo exhibitions at the Gorham Gallery in New York, the Corcoran Gallery in Washington, D.C., and the Pennsylvania Academy in Philadelphia. She was also invited to exhibit her bronzes at the Panama Pacific Exposition in San Francisco. In 1914 she executed a bronze statuette of Eleanora Duse for which the actress posed, and later completed portrait busts of Anna Pavlova and Ethel Barrimore.
In late 1917 in Paris, Ladd founded the American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks to provide cosmetic masks to be worn by men who had been badly disfigured in World War I. Her services earned her the Légion d'Honneur Crois de Chevalier and the Serbian Order of Saint Sava.
For many years, Ladd maintained a summer studio "Arden" at Beverly Farms in Manchester, Massachusetts. In 1923, she received an honorary degree of Master of Arts from Tufts College.
Anna Coleman Ladd died June 3, 1939 in Santa Barbara, California.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of sculptor Anna Coleman Ladd measure 4.2 linear feet, date from 1881-1950, and document the career of sculptor Anna Coleman Ladd. Found within the papers are biographical material, letters, diaries, financial material, notes and writings, art work, a file concerning the American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks, scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Biographical materials are scattered and include calling cards, biographical sketches notes, and certificates.
Correspondence includes letters written to Anna Coleman Ladd from various family members, friends, and colleagues. Notable correspodents include William Aldrich, Gabriella Fabbricotti, Isabella Stewart Gardner, Natalie Hays Hammond, and Jessie Eldridge Southwick.
Diaries are daily diaries dating from 1903-1905 and from 1911-1912. Each diary includes short descriptions of Ladd's days.
Financial materials include receipts, stock certificates, travel materials, lists, and an account book for Dr. Maynard Ladd.
Writings and notes consists of notebooks, lists of works of art, inventories, manuscripts by Ladd and by others.
Artworks include two sketchbooks, loose drawings, and a plaster relief by Ladd as well as several sketches by others.
American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks files include correspondence, writings, a scrapbook, printed materials, and photographs. Materials concern portrait masks used to disguise the disfigured faces of World War I veterans.
Scrapbooks consists of three scrapbooks containing photographs, printed materials, and writings.
Printed materials include clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Ladd's works, books and booklets, and posters, some of which are French World War I propaganda.
Photographs include photographs of Anna Coleman Ladd with her works of art and in the studio, Dr. Maynard Ladd, friends, family, colleagues, and works of sculpture.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 10 series. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1910-1950 (Box 1; 4 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1895-1937 (Box 1-2; 1.1 linear feet)
Series 3: Diaries, 1903-1912 (Box 2; 2 folders)
Series 4: Financial Material, 1899-1934 (Box 2; 6 folders)
Series 5: Writings and Notes, 1888-1949 (Box 2, 6, OV 7; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 6: Artwork, 1901-1928 (Box 2, 6, OV 7; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 7: American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks File, 1914-1925 (Box 2-3, 6; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 8: Scrapbooks, 1900-1940 (Box 3; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1889-1942 (Box 3, 6, OV 7; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, 1881-1932 (Box 4-6, MGP 1; 0.8 linear feet)
Existence and Location of Copies note
The collection was digitized in 2014 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Aldrich, William; American Red Cross. Studio for Portrait Masks (Paris, France).; Fabbricotti, Gabriella; Gardner, Isabella Stewart, 1840-1924; Hammond, Natalie Hays, 1905-; Southwick, Jessie Eldridge; Architectural sculpture; Artists' studios--Photographs; Diaries; Drawings; Photographs; Portrait sculpture; Scrapbooks; Sculptors--Massachusetts--Boston; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Women authors--Massachusetts--Boston; Women sculptors--Massachusetts--Boston; Works of art; World War, 1914-1918--France--Paris Portrait sculpture
- Biographical Material, circa 1905-1950; Series 1; 4 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes biographical and genealogical notes for Anna Coleman Ladd and the Ladd family, including an application to the WPA. There are also membership and award certificates.
  Arrangement note
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Calling Cards, circa 1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Genealogical Notes, circa 1910-circa 1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Certificates, 1910-1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1895-1937; Series 2; 1.1 Linear feet Box 1-2
  Letters are primarily from family members and friends including Countess Nora Balzani, Dr. Bindo de Vecchio, and painter Gabriella Fabbricotti. There are a few letters each from colleagues Emil Ahlborn, William Aldrich, Frances F. Brundage, Ralph Adams Cram, Willard Cummings, John Ettl, Isabella Stewart Gardner, Charles Grafly, Lilian Westcott Hale, Philip Leslie Hale, Natalie Hays Hammond, J. Scott Hartley, Malvina Hoffman, Anna Vaughn Hyatt, Leila Mechlin, Violet Oakley, Albin Polasek, Bertha Potter, Janet Scudder, Thomas Mott Shaw, Lorado Taft, and Rosamond Tudor. There are also letters from activists Elisabeth Achelis, Florence Peshine Eagleton, and Gabrielle Enthoven, actors Julie Opp Faversham, William Faversham, Frances Starr, and Gilda Varesi, composer Louisa P. Loring, dancers Beate Bolm, Michio Ito, and Anna Pavolva, and writers James Bryce, Maud Howe Elliott, Eirene Mungo-Park, Romain Rolland, Porter Sargent, Jessie Eldridge Southwick, and Riccardo Tramontano.
  Researchers should note that some correspondence is unsigned or illegible.
  Undated letters are arranged in alphabetical order and are found at the beginning of the series. The bulk of the correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  - Unidentified Correspondents and Fragments, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - First Names A-B, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - First Names C-G, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - First Names H-L, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - First Names M, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - First Names N, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - First Names P-Z, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Surnames A, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Surnames B, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Surnames C, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Surnames D-E, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Surnames F-G, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Surnames H, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Surnames I-K, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Surnames L, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Surnames M, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Surnames N-R, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Surnames S, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Surnames T-Z, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Anna Coleman Watts Ladd, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    (to her children, husband, and drafts to friends)
  - Gabrielle Ladd, circa 1920-circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Maynard Ladd, circa 1900-circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Vernon Abbott Ladd, circa 1920-circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letters, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Brown, Henry Hobart
  - Letters, 1897-1898 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Tom (maybe Thomas Mott Shaw) Trevelyn, Madeline
  - Letters, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Merrill, George Grenville
    Tom (maybe Thomas Mott Shaw)
  - Letters, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Baldwin, Abraham Rosencrans
    Ladd, Maynard
  - Letters, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Greene, Rosalind and Henry Copley
  - Letters, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Fabbricotti, Gabriella
  - Letters, 1903 Jan-May (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Balzani, Nora
  - Letters, 1903 Jun-Dec (Box 1, Folder 35)
    de Vecchio, Bindo
  - Letters, 1904 Jan-May (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Letters, 1904 Jun (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letters, 1904 Jul (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Watts, John
    Bryce, James
    MacMillan, Frederick
  - Letters, 1904 Aug (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Roosevelt, George
  - Letters, 1904 Sep (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Girolemo, F.
  - Letters, 1904 Oct (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Balzani, I.
  - Letters, 1904 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letters, 1905 Jan-Apr (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Letters, 1905 May (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Letters, 1905 Jun (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Mungo-Park, Eirene
    A., Nina
    Gentili (?), Ida
    Tejan (?), Bianca Bardo
    Potter, Bertha
  - Letters, 1905 Jul-Dec (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Perry, Blinn
    de Bellegarde, Nina
  - Letters, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Poole, Lavore
    Leroy, E.
    del Buono, Albert
  - Letters, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Holt, Henry
    Smith, Gertrude Robinson
  - Letters, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Sargent, Porter
    Fray, Ronald
    Mechlin, Leila
    French, W.M.R.
  - Letters, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Taft, Lorado
    Coolidge, J.R. Jr.
    Malcolm, Victoria
    Grafly, Charles
  - Letters, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Holt, Roland
  - Letters, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Macbeth, Robert Walker
    Brunetti, Jose
    Polasek, Albin
    Trask, John E.D.
    Borghese, Ann
    Scudder, Janet
    Phillips, Caroline Drayton
    Aldrich, William
  - Letters, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Zanelli, Angelo
    McKay, Helen
    Hale, Philip L.
    Ricker, Nettie M.
    Hartley, J. Scott
    Faversham, Julie Opp
    Faversham, William
  - Letters, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Tucker, Caroline
  - Letters, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Howland, Esther
  - Letters, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Powell, F.C.
    Kingston, Gertrude
  - Letters, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Southwick, Jessie Eldridge
    Boynton Monks
    Heard, Ralph Prescott
    Eggers, George W.
  - Letters, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Tramontano, Riccardo
    Tarbell, Ida
    Bolm, Beate
    Barttell, Mary F.
  - Letters, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Miller, E. Achelis
    Bochman, Mrs. Charles
    Oakley, Violet
  - Letters, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Brundage, Frances F.
    Forbes, Allan
    Gardner, Isabella Stewart
    Rollins, Mabel
    Barnard, George Grey
    Kelsey, Albert
    Sturgis, R. Clipston
    Harshe, Robert
  - Letters, 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Blake, William
  - Letters, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Tudor, Rosamond
    Pavlova, Anna
  - Letters, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Hayward, Alfred
    Megrew, Louise G.
  - Letters, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letters, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Kirk, Henry
    MacAusland, Andrew
    Minahan, Katharine
    Angel, John
    Achelis, Elisabeth
    Scarborough, Dorothy
  - Letters, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Clough, Clarence
    Picot, Colonel
    Rollard, Romain
  - Letters, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    de Marco, Etta de Vite
    McKenzie, R. Tait
    Shaw, Louis
  - Letters, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Williamson, J.
    Pollak-Ottendorff, Emil
    Fiske, Claire
  - Letters, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Morgan, Emily
    Frary, William
  - Letters, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Letters, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Diaries, 1903-1912; Series 3; 2 Folders Box 2
  The diaries contain brief annotations describing Ladd's daily activities. The diary dated 1903-1905 also contains a list of relief sculptures. The other diary has a hand-worked suede cover, and primarily annotates daily activities in 1911. There is also a page of annotations describing activities dating from January 20 to 27, 1912, with an additional page listing names.
  This series has been partially scanned. The diary dating from 1903-1905 has not been scanned due to the fragility of the document.
  - Diary, 1903-1905 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Diary, 1911-1912 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Financial Material, 1899-1934; Series 4; 6 Folders Box 2
  Financial material consists of receipts for the sale of art work and for travel, stock certificates for the Alliance Oil Company, and a promissory note and account book relating to Maynard Ladd's medical practice.
  - Promissory Note from Maynard Ladd, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Travel Receipts, 1903-1917 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Sales Lists and Receipts for Art Work, 1911-1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Stock Certificates for the Alliance Oil Company, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Accounts Book for Dr. Maynard Ladd, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Notes and Writings, 1888-1949; Series 5; 0.6 Linear feet Box 2, 6, OV 7
  This series consists of notebooks and manuscripts written by Anna Coleman Ladd and by others, some of which are illustrated by Ladd. Notebook 1 primarily contains lists of mythological and allegorical characters. Notebook 2 contains historical notes, listings of Italian authors and painters, poems, clippings, three drawings, and an illustrated letter. Notebook 3 contains notes from a class in composition. Notebook 4 contains lists of friends' names and poetry.
  The guest register contains autographs of William Aldrich, Senator Albert J. Beveridge, Gabriella Fabbricotti, Isabella Stewart Gardner, Philip Leslie Hale, John Hays Hammond, Marie Danforth Page, Agnes Repplier, John Singer Sargent, Frances Starr. There are two small hand-made books by Anna Coleman Watts and Gabriella Fabbricotta. Miscellaneous poems include the poem "Hymn for Easter" by Dorothy Grafly.
  - Notebook 1, circa 1910 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Notebook 2, circa 1910 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - Notebook 3, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Notebook 4, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Guest Register, 1912-1918 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Lists of Guests, circa 1910-1929 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Lists of Sculpture by Anna Coleman Ladd, circa 1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - List of Sitters for Portraits, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Lists of Photographs, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Notes for Blue Prints and Blue Prints, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6 and OV 7
  - Inventories of Art Work and Miscellaneous Possessions, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Lecture about Being a Sculptor, circa 1930 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Act IV of an Unidentified Play, circa 1910s (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Hidden Gardens, circa 1910s (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - The Young Prince, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Part I, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 1, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 2-4, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 5-7, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 8-10, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 13, 17-18, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 20-23, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 24-29, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 30, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 33, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 34, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 37-38, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Drawings, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Galleys, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - The Strong: Drama in Four Acts, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 52-54)
  - Miscellaneous Writings with Illustrations, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Writings by Anna Coleman Ladd, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Hand-Made Booklet The Hangman's Daughter, by Gabriella Fabbricotti, circa 1910 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous Poems by Others, 1902-1949 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Oversized Notes and Blue Prints for Miscellaneous Sculpture Projects, 1923-1925 (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F32
  - Oversized Blue Prints for Michael J. Cadigan Post 46 Stele, 1923 (Box OV 7)
- Artwork, 1901-1928; Series 6; 0.2 Linear feet Box 2, 6, OV 7
  Art work consists of sketchbooks, drawings, and a small plaster relief sculpture by Anna Coleman Ladd. Art work by others includes a drawing of Mademoiselle Monnier by E. Briant, a watercolor sketch by E. Hunter, and a cut-out silhouette of a woman.
  - Sketchbook 1, circa 1900-circa 1930s (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Sketchbook 2, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Drawings by Anna Coleman Ladd, 1902-1905 (Box 2, Folder 61-62)
  - Art Work by Others, 1901-1928 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Plaster Relief Sculpture by Anna Coleman Ladd, circa 1910 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6
  - Oversized Drawings and Oversized Relief Sculpture, circa 1910 (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F62, 64
  - Oversized Drawings, Tracings, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box OV 7)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F62
- American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks File, 1914-1925; Series 7; 0.4 Linear feet Box 2-3, 6
  This series contains material relating to Ladd's services aiding soldiers badly disfigured during World War I. Ladd established a studio in Paris in which she fashioned cosmetic masks to be worn by soldiers with terrible facial wounds. The notes and writings include a small notebook of price lists for sculptures. The scrapbook contains letters, clippings, and photographs of Maynard Ladd in the trenches, and of disfigured soldiers both with and without their masks.
  - Letters, 1919-1925 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Notes and Writings, circa 1914-1925 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1933 (Box 2, Folder 67-73)
  - Printed Material, 1916-1918 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1914-1925 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Photographs, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 3, F2
- Scrapbooks, 1900-1940; Series 8; 0.3 Linear feet Box 3
  Scrapbook 1 primarily contains photographs, clippings, and postcards showing works of art and architecture. Scrapbook 2 contains photographs of Ladd and her work, notes and writings, and clippings. Scrapbook 3 contains photographs of art work, a writing entitled "Jesus and the Sleeping Child," a booklet, and clippings.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940 (Box 3, Folder 4-12)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1923-1936 (Box 3, Folder 13-19)
- Printed Material, 1889-1942; Series 9; 0.5 Linear feet Box 3, 6, OV 7
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, programs, prospectuses, posters, brochures, autographed menus, booklets, and books. The programs are from Salisbury Cathedral, the Park Theatre, and Vassar College. The posters primarily reflect World War I topics including warnings against gas bombs. Brochures are primarily for lectures by Ladd. The menu dated 1921 is autographed by Cass Gilbert and Alfred Harding, Bishop of Washington. The books Meditations in Verse and Sundial Mottoes are autographed by the authors. Miscellaneous printed material includes engravings of anatomical diagrams.
  This series has been partially scanned. Only relevant pages of exhibition announcements with multiple artists and the covers, title pages, and relevant pages of published books have been scanned.
  - Clippings, circa 1910-1930 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1930-1942 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1920 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1916-1920 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1921-1925 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1930-1938 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Programs, 1905-1930 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Prospectuses, 1914-1916 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Posters, 1902-1918 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, OV 7
  - Brochures, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Autographed Menus, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - "Contemporary American Sculptors,", circa 1914 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - "Le Procès de Jeanne d'Arc", as Presented by Madame Sarah Bernhardt, circa 1916 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - "A Vindication of President H. O. Ladd,", 1889 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "Monographien zur Weltgeschichte,", 1898 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - "Hedwige D'Anjou," by M. Stanislas Smolka, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - "Mura Urbane,", 1911 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "National Sculpture Society Constitution, Officers and Members," (1914-1915);"National Sculpture Society Constitution, Officers and Members," (1924-1925), 1914-1925 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "Sculpture and Mural Paintings of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition,", 1915 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - "Official Miniature View Book of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition; Panama-Pacific International Exposition Report of the Department of Fine Arts", 1915 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - "Tre Figure Scomparse,", 1915 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - "Le Livre Rouge des Atrocités Allemandes,", 1916 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - "The Captivity of the Italians in Austria,", 1918 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - "La Petite Illustration Théatrale,", 1919 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "The Work of Anna Coleman Ladd,", 1920 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - "Year Book of Poems,", 1925 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "Gli Amori di Greta Garbo,", 1930 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - "Third Reunion Bulletin of the Class of 1927,", 1931 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    (Vassar College)
  - "Le Manuscript Autographe,", 1933 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Epigrammes by Paul Verlaine, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Meditations in Verse by Jessie Eldridge Southwick, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - A Child Went Forth by Yoï Pawlowska, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Sundial Mottoes by Margaret L. Corlies, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art, 1913-1920 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Awards, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Newsletters, 1914-1915 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Oversized Printed Material, 1920 (Box 6)